The eye of the enemy is moving.
The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King is a adventure,
fantasy, action film directed by Peter Jackson.
As armies mass for a final battle that will decide the fate of the world--and powerful, ancient forces of Light and Dark compete to
determine the outcome--one member of the Fellowship of the Ring is revealed as the noble heir to the throne of the Kings of Men.
Yet, the sole hope for triumph over evil lies with a brave hobbit, Frodo, who, accompanied by his loyal friend Sam and the hideous, wretched
Gollum, ventures deep into the very dark heart of Mordor on his seemingly impossible quest to destroy the Ring of Power.​
Frodo, played by Elijah Wood.
Gandalf, played by Ian McKellen.
Aragorn, played by Viggo Mortensen.
Sam, played by Sean Astin.
Gollum / Smeagol, played by Andy Serkis.
Merry, played by Dominic Monaghan.
The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King is a 2003 hack and slash game
developed by EA Redwood Shores for the PlayStation 2 and Windows.
It was ported to the GameCube and Xbox by Hypnos Entertainment, to the Game Boy Advance by
Griptonite Games, to mobile by ImaginEngine, and to Mac OS X by Beenox.
The game was published by Electronic Arts.
It is the sequel to the 2002 game The Lord of the Rings: The Two Towers.
The game is an adaptation of Peter Jackson's 2002 film The Lord of the Rings: The Two Towers and his 2003
film The Lord of the Rings: The Return of the King, which was released shortly after the game.
As it is not an adaptation of J.
Tolkien's 1954 novel, The Return of the King, the third volume in Lord of the Rings, anything from the novel
not specifically mentioned or depicted in the films could not be represented in the game.
This is because, at the time, Vivendi Universal Games, in partnership with Tolkien Enterprises, held the rights to the video game adaptations
of Tolkien's literary works, whilst Electronic Arts held the rights to the video game adaptations of the New Line Cinema films.
The game is similar to its predecessor in basic gameplay, but differs by adding multiple
storylines, more playable characters and increased interaction with environments.
A two-player co-op mode is also available for some missions.
As with The Two Towers, The Return of the King was developed in close collaboration with the filmmakers, using
many of the actual reference photos, drawings, models, props and other assets from the film.
The game was met with positive critical reception for its graphics, audio, and
gameplay, although its camera positioning and short length were criticized.
The film explores themes of army, based on novel or book, elves, dwarf, magic.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.